-- Usagi Drop 02 --
Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush.
Anything else?
Huh?!
Rin, don't just leave my side like that!
You scared me!
Okay.
Daikichi, get me a green one.
Alright, let's go.
It's dangerous if we don't hold hands.
Dangerous for me?
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
Were there always this many parents and children here?
I want that one.
This?
Yeah.
Um, okay. Looks good.
What size are you?
I don't know.
Rin, turn around.
Like this?
Where should I measure it from?
I don't know.
Stop flapping!
What else do you need?
Pajamas, underwear, shirts, socks!
Don't you want some skirts too?
These are all pants.
They don't allow skirts at the daycare.
I see.
Daycare?!
I completely forgot!
Tomorrow's Monday!
Daikichi, I'm tired.
Just hang on, we're almost there.
Okay.
I'm hungry.
We're almost home.
Okay.
Could you get that?
Hello, Maeda residence.
Oh, I'm so sorry to hear about your family's loss.
Yes, just a moment.
Haruko-san, it's Daikichi-san.
Oh, okay. Coming!
Haruko?
Sorry, I didn't have your cell phone number.
It's okay.
Say, how do I enter a kid into a daycare?
Daycare?
So you really did take Rin-chan home?!
Are things okay?
For the time being.
What do you mean?
The thing is, I can't take tomorrow off.
What's the proper protocol here?
Well, daycares don't just let kids in that easily.
Couldn't you do something?
I'm not sure what I could do.
I guess for now you could ask at city hall.
It's Sunday night.
What's wrong?
Nothing, it's on my end.
Mama, is that Rin-chan?
Are you okay?
Rin-chan!
Stop it, Reina! This is important.
There's an emergency short-term daycare.
An emergency short-term daycare?
Rin-chan!
What's wrong, Dai-chan?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Nothing, it's on my end.
Just hold on, I'm almost done!
I'm tired of waiting!
Haruko-san, the miso soup is about done.
Oh, thank you.
It sounds like you're busy. I'll call later -
Rin-chan!
Osu City Hall
Emergency Short-term
Sports Day for Parents and Kids
City Hall Site Map
Daycare
Man, there's so few of them!
My commuting time just doubled.
Yeah, I'm okay.
This one's not too far, but I can't leave the office at six.
Let's play again.
Okay. Bye-bye, Reina-chan.
Take care.
This one looks good, but it only
provides emergency care for ten days.
Bath.
Just a minute.
Daikichi! Daikichi!
It's morning.
Right, sorry.
Did you sleep here?
Why's it so warm here?
Take this off!
Okay, okay.
So about the daycare we're going to today...
Thank you for this meal.
You shouldn't have your elbow on the table when you eat!
Right, sorry.
Listen, the daycare we're going to today is only a temporary one.
Temporary?
It means you'll be there until we find a place that'll let you officially enter.
What's "officially" mean?
Like properly.
Actually, that's not right.
My hair's fine!
You okay?
I'm okay.
Are you okay?
There it is!
Put me down! Put me down!
What's wrong?
Embarrassed that the other kids might see me carrying you?
What the...?
Daikichi.
Right.
I'll leave her with you then.
Okay, see you later!
What's with that face?
I can't say I'll be back before it gets dark,
but I'll get here as fast as I can.
I promise.
I pinky promise.
If I lie, I'll swallow a thousand needles.
Damn those needles.
Pinky break!
That's not the right song.
I'm off. Wait for me, Rin.
I'm sorry, Rin.
I didn't realize how you were feeling.
Your mom's disappearance and Grandpa's death had nothing to do with you.
And yet you're the only one left to face that lonely reality.
Did you think I was going to leave you behind as well?
I'm sorry.
That won't happen ever again.
Can you read this?
Sure.
Kawachi-san, wanna grab a bite?
I brought my own.
I have to leave a little early today.
Oh, really? Alright then, see you.
You're going all out, right from the start of the month, huh?
Nope.
Take a picture of this sample.
Okay.
Kawachi-san, there's a caller on line four asking about the private audience.
On my way.
Yes, this is Kawachi.
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye.
Let's keep going!
Okay.
Kawachi.
Right, sorry.
You're late!
Sorry, sorry. Go change.
Okay!
Rin-chan, don't bring it down, okay?
Okay.
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye.
Yes, please wait a moment.
Kawachi-san.
It's Miyata-san from Mitsutomo Commerce.
Transfer him to me.
Yes, this is Kawachi.
We appreciate your business.
Hello, this is Kawachi.
Yes, I'm so sorry.
Yes, I'll be able to leave in just a bit.
I'm sorry.
This daycare is so far!
Rin, sorry I'm late!
Welcome back.
I'm so sorry.
Rin.
Whoa, potatoes! They look delicious.
They're chopped vegetables!
Daikichi
I swallowed...
a thousand needles.
Here you go.
Kawachi-san, I need you to sign!
I may just be a worrywart,
but what should I do if I get a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Right, sorry.
Kawachi, you shipped this out yesterday, right?
I'm so sorry.
It's unusual for you to mess up.
Forgive me.
I already apologized to the customer.
Sorry, I'll call them too.
Let's go for a drink later. It has been a while.
Sorry, I can't tonight.
How about tomorrow?
Tomorrow's no good, either.
I get it. Way to go.
Climb on.
I'm fine.
Daikichi!
You better hold on!
Daikichi, don't let the moon catch us!
Got it!
This'll never end!
How long can I continue living like this?
These are Rin-chan's.
The child care handbook and important documents are all she has.
It might only be for a short time,
but raising a child is very difficult.
Isn't it Rin who's got the worst end?
Sorry, but I'm just going to look for a second.
Her mouth hasn't changed.
The rest of my family speak as if you were a villain or something.
What's the true story, Masako-san?
Maternity and Child
Care Handbook
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
What's wrong?
Are you sick?
By the way, when did you start sleeping on that side?
Was that me?!
It's sweat!
Okay, fine. It's sweat.
Help me remove the sheets.
I said it's sweat!
I'm saying it's sweat too!